Rathakate Hanchana

Tel: (66) 99 161 3592 | Email: Rathakate @gmail.com

Address: 581/123 city home, Ratchadapisek road, Soi 10, Huaykhwang, Bangkok, 10310

Linked in: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rathakate-hanchana-148b0616



Professional Attributes

With more than 20 years' of experience in management, I am excellent in working with others to achieve a certain objective on time and with excellence solution, especially in Digital service for across industry of TELCO and IT. I am an open-minded, friendly and resourceful management and also strong ambitious person who has developed a mature and responsible approach to any target that I undertake.

Skills

Project Management
Digital service planning
UI/UX
Portfolio management
CAPEX/OPEX control









Master Degree in Computer Science, Software Engineering

Faculty of Computer engineering, Chulalongkorn University

Project Management Professional (PMP), credential number 1222386

Project Management Institute

Work Experience

2014 - Present



Vice President ,Service Planning department ,Technology group

Key responsible:

To manage service planning department as per following key deliverables

- 1) Initiative business development of digital Service /product for DTAC which include various area of digital business: Mobile advertising ,Location base services ,Mobile tv, live broadcast, VAS services enhancement, customer experience improvement ,IoTs M2M,all Cloud services ,RCS ,IMS solution and partner management
- 2) Development strategy together with marketing business unit for short -term and long term of Digital Services to alignment with Telenor group strategy
- 3) Monitoring and control financial unit, part of OPEX,CAPEX for IT deliverables 4) Monitoring and control portfolio management for VAS, Digital platform, Infrastructure

Key deliverables: Digital services (RCS, IoTs, IT transformation and new initiative startup services)

2012 - 2014



Nokia project Manager: oversees the planning, implementation, and tracking of a specific project for Nokia's client

Key responsible:

- -Define the scope of the project in collaboration with senior management
- -Create a detailed work plan which identifies and sequences the activities needed to successfully complete the project
- -Determine the resources (time, money, equipment, etc) required to complete the project
- -Develop a schedule for project completion that effectively allocates the resources to the activities
- Review the project schedule with senior management and all other staff that will be affected by the project activities; revise the schedule as required
- Determine the objectives and measures upon which the project will be evaluated at its completion

Key deliverables:

- 1) VAS solution project (location base services): VietTel Mobile, Vietnam
- 2) Lawful interception project: Mobiphone, Vietnam
- 3) Charging service project Mobiphone, Vietnam
- 4) Entitle VAS solution for greenfield 3G project : TOT public company Limited, Thailand

2009 - 2012



Ericsson Project Manager: to oversees the planning, implementation, and tracking of a specific project for Ericsson indo-china market

Key responsible:

- -agreeing project objectives
- -representing the client's or organization's interests
- -organizing the various professional people working on a project
- -carrying out risk assessment
- -making sure that all the aims of the project are met
- -making sure the quality standards are met
- -overseeing the accounting, costing and billing

Kev deliverables:

- 1) Greenfield deliverable entitle VAS project on 3G network (CAADCOM, Cambodia)
 - -SMS,MMS, Welcome message
 - -SDP
 - -RBT
- 2) Streaming project (Dtac ,Thailand)
- 3) Network Audit project (CAADCOM, Cambodia

2007 - 2009



Customer Project Manager

Key responsible:

Oversees the planning, implementation, and tracking of a specific short-term project and long-term project for Huawei 'clients in Thailand market.

Key deliverables:

- 1) NGN network transformation (TrueMove, Public Company Limited)
- 2) VAS solution (SMS,MMS, Welcome message) (TrueMove,Public Company Limited)
- 3) Transmission network (TOT Public Company Limited)

Professional training

Listed only highlight training program

2015-2016 IT Transformation ,Startup business

development for TELCO/IT industry

Digital service design

Management of IT diversity

2014-2015 IoT,M2M and TELCO monetization

People management

User-experience management

Big data and transformation

2012-2014 Risk and response management

IMS transformation program

SIX sigma and project control scope